hey guys this is a very short
announcement about our online course
which is called sense-making 101 and
we're really excited because we have a
really great faculty on board to help us
teach the course and so yeah you want to
talk more about what people are going to
learn on since making 101 so we've put a
lot of time and thought into designing
this course and probably the easiest way
to describe it is that it moves from the
inside out so the more we've explored
concepts like sense making or collective
intelligence on the channel the more
it's become clear that in order for that
to happen in order for us to have you
know emergent conversations or
conversations that go somewhere that we
might not be expecting there's actually
a toolkit of skills we need yeah and I
think it's important to say that we've
been running retreats together like we
both trained as as counselors a couple
of years ago we've been running retreat
together mainly men's retreats this is
not going to be a men only course it's
gonna be a mixed course and so we've got
some experience with doing that in real
life and now we're trying to bring it a
bit more into the ideas that we've got
on the channel and then into the sort of
the wider online community and but we're
not doing it alone we've got an amazing
faculty who were gonna be helping us out
with it as well and we wanted to play
some clips from each of them to give it
a bit more of a sense of what they'll be
delivering on the course so we're gonna
start with someone a lot of people might
be familiar with daniel trachtenberg our
earnestness and sincerity empowered by
really deep courage and a deep kind of
epistemic humility is going to make
someone misfit for every end group
currently which is the valley crossing
that people have to go through to
basically leave the forces that are
irate arrayed in a war that we're all
sides are wronged to hopefully have
enough people who do that that start to
find each other and don't do a new
tribal groupthink thing but all engage
in earnest actual thinking themselves an
actual conversation without orienting
towards groupthink
that can start to make a new strange
attractor so another favorite the
channel is Jon bovi key he's become a
kind of bit of a cult hit online with
his
awakening from the meaning crisis series
and I went out recently and spend a bit
of time with him in Toronto and recorded
this field that we'll be going out in
the next couple of days where he talks
about and this is what is me talking
about in the course is wisdom what is
wisdom and how do we embody it because
it's much more than just a cognitive or
an ideas based thing
what is self-deception what are higher
states of consciousness what is
enlightenment what is wisdom what's our
best cognitive scientific answer that
and then can we use that to create what
I call psycho technologies and
communities and ecologies of them that
can give us back the cultivation of
wisdom and self transcendence and also
connect us up to a world of you that
valorizes homes legitimates and make
sense of that set of practices so we
also have Diane musho Hamilton who's an
award-winning mediator and also a
meditation instructor and Diane has a
lot of expertise around the area of
collective intelligence and in this clip
she's talking about this other aspect
that's quite closely related to it which
is coherence and about how this process
of being in and out of coherence and the
difference between coherence and
difference is really essential for
collective intelligence my experiences
create a lot of coherence and then
heightened difference boom and then you
start to experience emergence and how to
heighten difference is the skillset
we're always trying to move everybody
towards sameness and we're trying to
move everybody towards coherence but
actually what we need to be doing is
helping people calibrate and move
together highly coherently and then
really experience difference as it
arises on an embodied level within the
interaction notice when it flips into
threat and try to calibrate difference
and teach people how to be in difference
because that's where emergence is more
likely to to really make itself to
really come forward as to this collision
of difference that's what happens and
then we also have dough Xin Roshi
who is delivering a session on the
shadow which is a really core concept
and one he's really an expert in fact
he's known as the the shadow Roshi so
play clip from him we have to have
collective ways of dealing with this
collective shadow and we've developed
some some collective shadow work some
group shadow work where we we really
talk about these shadows and we work on
them and we help people become conscious
of them so we thought long and hard
about how to structure the course in the
best way and what we're gonna deliver is
an eight-week process and it's really a
mix of working together so working in
small groups having sessions with a live
lesson and QA with the teacher also
access anytime you want to exclusive
interviews we've recorded with them and
as well as that we have a pretty
detailed course booklet so you can do
kind of further your study as you have
time to do so throughout the whole
course the course will be starting at
beginning of March and there will be
limited places if you've got any queries
about it we've just created an email
address for it that's going to appear on
screen now unless I forget so if you
want to ask any more questions about it
just send us an email to that and yeah
go to the website the website is in the
show notes below and hope to see you
soon
you